JOSEPHINE B. PEACOCK

Email: josie.peacock0130@gmail.com
Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/josiebpeacock

SUMMARY

Over 25 years of experience with automation, test systems, project management, data acquisition, lean processes, calibration, and software development. Focus has been on sustaining, creating, and maintaining test systems, including software, of all forms used in final quality control and engineering solutions worldwide.

The most successful solutions come from an open mind towards the issues at hand and listening to opposing or different ideas with a receptive, respectful attitude.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Accurate Technology and Test Automation LLC (ATTA), Tulsa, OK, USA 2017-present Managing Director, April 2017 to Present

- Created Python based software solution that communicates with Allen Bradley *Logix devices using a RESTful API. Designed to be extensible for additional industrial protocols.
- Worked with MySQL, Redis, JSON, HTML5, Javascript, and Flask to build web app.
- Deployment of software using Ansible on AWS and local thin server.
- Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT) software solutions for data acquisition, aggregation, analysis, and machine control.
- Developed standardized Modular Control System (MCS) designed for flexibility and easy installation of test systems used in the field.
- Software and hardware solutions increased productivity for one customer by 60% and paid for itself in less than 6 months on the first installed test system.
- Provided remote support for customers with IT issues related to test systems.
- Worked with valve company to improve performance of newly designed control valve.

Schlumberger Contractor, Singapore

2017

Trainer, Jan 16 to Jan 26, 2017

- Led class on existing calibration, troubleshooting, and service of test systems.
- Trained people on the proper technique to train new people to work with these test systems.
- Worked with a team to help plan for the future of the Schlumberger test systems and service centers.

Schlumberger, Bartlesville, OK, USA

2000-2016

Electrical Engineer, HPS Group, 2015 to 2016

Designed and sustained electrical systems for Schlumberger Horizontal Pump System product line.

- Wrote Python programs to automate production. Cut time required to create data books by 50%.
- Automated Excel spreadsheets using VBA macros.
- Created and updated AutoCAD electrical drawings.
- Specified new electrical instrumentation and automation components for product design.
- Oversaw root cause analysis of electrical production issues.

JOSEPHINE B. PEACOCK

Email: josie.peacock0130@gmail.com
Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/josiebpeacock

Controls Engineer, Service Center Tooling, 2013 to 2015

Designed and sustained control systems and electrical systems for the Schlumberger test system product line. This included Pump Test, Motor Test, Cable Test, and Protector Test.

- Streamlined automated test systems designs using new technology.
- Automated test system controls and operation expert.
- Supported technical issues and quality control of test system manufacturing.
- Created BOM's for new test system developments and previous system upgrades.

ART-C Support Engineer, Assembly Repair and Test Center (ART-C) Support, 2006 to 2013 Serviced, upgraded, installed, and certified test systems at over 30 locations worldwide.

- Managed installation of high spec data acquisition system for a \$1.5 Billion Petrobras project.
- Team member for design of test system to meet Petrobras requirements.
- Developed budgets for test system improvement projects.
- Coordinated shipment of calibration equipment and required visas for travel.
- Trained personnel to calibrate and certify test systems.
- Worked with vendors and outside contractors to complete tasks.
- Programmed PLC and HMI for test systems.
- System integrator of several dissimilar components.

Electronic Technician. Maintenance. 2001 to 2006

Troubleshot, repaired, and maintained various automated machines.

- Produced easily understood procedures for common processes in maintenance.
- General troubleshooting, repair, and maintenance of a variety of automated machines.

EDUCATION / TRAINING

Associates, Electronics Engineering Technology, ITT Technical Institute

ControlLogix/Studio 5000 Logix Designer, Rockwell Automation

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, HTML, Javascript, JSON, RESTful API, Flask, Redis, MySQL, Git, PLC Ladder, HMI

Industrial Hardware: Allen Bradley, Red Lion, Schneider Electric, Modicon, Magelis, Emerson, Fanuc, Mazak, National Instruments, Kollmorgen

Software: Studio 5000, Crimson, Unity Pro, TwidoSuite, Vijeo, PL7, National Instruments, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Powerpoint, Microsoft Word, AutoCAD

Operating Systems: Windows, Ubuntu Linux

Industrial Protocols: Ethernet/IP, RS485 ASCII, RS485 Modbus, RS232 Serial, CAN bus, Modbus TCP/IP, HART protocol